ANDY ANDERSON

WEB DEVELOPER

■ andy@andyanderson.io • andyanderson.io • 4193208678 in /in/andyanderson1817 • AAnderson1817

SUMMARY

Innovation-driven developer with extensive experience in creative leadership and administration. I embrace Kaizen—the principle of continuous active improvement.

Let's pioneer solutions to connect the world and accelerate access to technology so humanity can collaborate for the benefit of all. This is the fundamental reason I entered the frontier of the tech industry and continue to advocate for virtual reality as an interactive medium and catalyst for change.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Web Development Immersive

The Ohio State University BA Theatre 2012

SKILLS

Javascript | HTML5 | CSS3 | React | AngularJS | JQuery | Express | Node | Mongo | PostgreSQL | Wordpress | Sass | Bootstrap | JSON |

PROJECTS

How Do I Sound?

"How Do I Sound?" is a tool that analyzes the social and emotional tones of a user's emails, texts, or other communiqué. Using this feedback, users can adapt their messages to come across as friendlier, more agreeable, and confident.

Technologies: HTML5 | CSS3 | Sass | Javascript | Mongo | Express | Angular | Node.js | JSON | API | Bootstrap

Conduit

"Conduit" is an event platform providing users the ability to pull from multiple resources like Meetup, Ticketmaster, and Eventful to create a list of activities personally curated to the user's specifications.

Technologies: HTML5 | CSS3 | Javascript | JQuery | Mongo | Express | Angular | Node.js | JSON | API

Do

"Do" is a straightforward app using Ruby on Rails designed to categorize a user's goals into four fundamental facets utilizing CRUD functionality.

Technologies: HTML5 | CSS3 | Javascript | Ruby on Rails | PostGreSQL |

Mysterious Console

In "Mysterious Console", users assume the role of characters happening upon a sinister, archaic computer terminal in the woods.

Technologies: HTML5 | CSS3 | Javascript | Bootstrap

EMPLOYMENT

Web Developer/Technical Liaison

Venbord

Nov 2016 to Current

For the curious, the primary responsibility of a technology liaison is to represent the needs of a company's business personnel to technical planning groups in IT, and, likewise, to represent the needs of IT to the business customers. Working closely with and often embedded into the business community, this liaison develops a solid understanding of how business operations function. The liaison then identifies improvement opportunities and defines technical requirements to help IT teams design hardware or software solutions. Essentially, the liaison serves as a bridge linking the business community and IT to ensure the services IT provides align efficiently with the needs of the business. In my role as Technical Liaison for Venbord, I work closely with the founders, providing consulting to shape the technical blueprint of our app. The role is multi-faceted. Many of my day-to-day responsibilities involve market research, site-prototyping, and studying relevant languages. Currently, I'm learning Unity for a visual interface and React for a robust interactive experience.

UI Consultant

Chalksphere

2016 to Current

ChalkSphere is an education-centered app deployed in India designed to help teachers, administrators, parents, and students stay current with each other. Presently, I am conducting research to help shape ChalkSphere's UI to better suit an American audience.

Full-Stack Developer

Ballparq.io

Nov 2016 to Jan 2017

Ballparq is a financial platform designed to streamline and simplify the startup process for entrepreneurs. I helped lead a team of 3 developers in creating interactive onboarding methods that capture the eye and incite action.